A Guide to the Island Resources Foundation records FA1200
Rockefeller Archive Center
Island Resources Foundation records
1853, 1894-1895, 1898, 1925, 1935, 1944, 1946-1947, 1949, 1953-1956, 1958-2016
Rockefeller Archive Center
Island Resources Foundation (United States Virgin Islands)
FA1200
73.62 Cubic Feet 190 letter document boxes 1 legal document box 1 1/2 letter document box
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports, correspondence, audiovisual materials (videos, photographs and negatives), and publications.
The collection is about the Caribbean Islands and their history and settlements, economic growth and challenges, tourism, and environmental issues. Project-based research, educational outreach, information sharing, technical expertise and capacity building.
Biographical / Historical
Island Resources Foundation (IRF) was established in 1972 in St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands as a Caribbean-based, small-island-focused, and environment-themed non-governmental organization. The foundation decided to shut down in 2016. Their mission was often project-based research, educational outreach, information sharing, technical expertise and capacity building.
The IRF was founded by Ed Towle, who was also the first president from 1972-1998. Without his influence the emergence of a conservation ethic in the Caribbean in the 1960s and 1970s would have been less intellectually rigorous, less open and expansive in its outreach, and less sustainable during a time when the region had other priorities.
Arrangement
Series 1-Administrative and Financial. Series 2-Couuntries. Series 3-Project and Occasional Papers. Series 4-General Correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Caribbean Area; Environmental monitoring; Biodiversity
- Administrative and Financial, 1970-2016; 1; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - Articles of Incorporation, Original, 1970, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation, Admendments, 1970-1971, 1974, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Historical Record (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting, 1974-1991, 1993-2008, 2010-2014 (Box 1, Folder 4-33)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting, 2014-2016 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Board of Trustees, Meetings, Notices, Agendas, and Proxies, 1973-1974, 1978-1980, 1983-1985, 1987, 1990-1991, 1993-1994, 1996, 2010, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1972-1973, 1977-1986, 1988-1995, 1996-2006, 2008, 2010-2016 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - By-Laws, Original, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - By-Laws, Admendments, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Capability Statement, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Caribbean Information Initiatives, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Electronic Mailing Lists, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Grants and Contracts Funded by Philanthropic Groups and Non-US Governments and Agencies (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Interns, Historical Record, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Members, Solicitation Letters, 1973-1979, 1981-1988, 1996, 1999-2000, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Annual Reports, Bulletins, and Year-in-Review, 1976-1982, 1984-2005, 2007-2011, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Policies and Procedures, 1976-1980, 1988-1989, 1991, 2003, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Program Associates, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Programs Funded by the United States Government (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Programs Funded by the Virgin Islands and Puerto Rican Government (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Progress Reports, and Project Activities Summaries, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Prospectus and Program Plan, Revision and Additional Information (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Publications List (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Reference Library, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Summary of Island Resources Foundation Projects, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Tax Exemption Letter, United States Government, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Tax Exemption Letter, United States Virgin Islands Government, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Virgin Islands Resource Management Cooperative (VIRMC) Publications "Flyer", 1989 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Remembering Edward Leon Towle, Jr., 2006 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Remembering Edward Leon Towle, Jr.-A Memorial Celebration of the Life of Edward Leon Towle, Jr., Ph. D., 2006 December 2 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Audit, 1971-1975, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Financial Report, 1976-2015, 1977-2016 (Box 3, Folder 60-95)
- Countries, 1853, 1898, 1925, 1935, 1944, 1946-1947, 1949, 1953-1955, 1958-1961, 1963-2016; 2; 29.03 Cubic Feet 73 letter document boxes, 1 legal document box and 1 flat file folder
  Hazard Mitigation
  - Anguilla, General Information, Economy, History, Archaeology, Development, and Tourism, 1980, 1985-1987, 1992, 1994, 1999, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    Separated Materials
    Removed still slides
  - Anguilla, Reports, 1977, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 97-98)
  - Anguilla, Clippings, 1979-1980, 1987-1988, 1990, 1992, 1994, 1997-1998, 2000, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Anguilla, Anguilla Conservation Society, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Anguilla, Anguilla National Trust, Correspondence, 1992-1997, 1999-2000, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Anguilla, Anguilla National Trust, Newsletters, Brochures, and Information (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Anguilla, East Caribbean Institute of Development, 1986, 1989, 1991-1993, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Anguilla, Sombrero Islands, 1926, 1978, 1985, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 104-105)
  - Anguilla, Sombrero Island, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Antigua, General Information, Economy, Development, and Tourism, 1982-1983, 1986-1992, 1995-1998, 2004, 2008, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 107-109)
  - Antigua, Clippings, 1979, 1986, 1989-1990, 1994, 1996-1999, 2001, 2004, 2007, 2009-2011 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Antigua, Agriculture, Land Use, Environmental Legislation, and Biodiversity, 1980, 1983, 2000-2001, 2005-2006, 2008, 2010-2013 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Antigua, Agriculture, Land Use, Environmental Legislation, and Biodiversity, 1935, 1944, 1953, 1957, 1973-1974, 1980, 1984-1988, 1993-2000, 2002, 2005-2006, 2008-2010 (Box 6, Folder 112-114)
  - Antigua, Coastal/Marine Resources, Historic/Archaeological Sites, 1972, 1979, 1984-1985, 1987-1990, 1993, 1995-1996, 1998-2004, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 115-117)
  - Antigua, Coastal/Marine Resources, Historic/Archaeological Sites, 1973-1974, 1979-1980, 1990, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Antigua, Coastal/Marine Resources, Historic/Archaeological Sites, Dow's Hill Marine Training, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - Antigua and Barbuda, Environmental Profile, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - Antigua, Miscellaneous Reports, 1988, 1992, 1994, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 121-123)
  - Antigua, Miscellaneous Reports, 1999-2000, 2006, 2009, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 124-126)
  - Antigua, Betty's Hope Estate, Newsletter, Brochure, and Information, 1989-1990, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Antigua, Betty's Hope Estate, Management Plan for Betty's Hope Historical Sugar Plantation (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Antigua, Cooperative Farmers Association, Questionnaire, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Antigua, Cooperative Farmers Association, Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Antigua, East Caribbean Institute of Development, 1986-1995 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Antigua, Environmental Awareness Group, Correspondence, 1989-1992, 1994-1995, 1998-2005, 2008, 2010-2011, 2013-2014 (Box 8, Folder 132-133)
  - Antigua, Environmental Awareness Group, Institutional Development Plan, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Antigua, Environmental Awareness Group, Newsletters, Reports, and Documents, 1989-1990, 1992-1994, 1996-2007, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 135-136)
  - Antigua and Barbuda, Fisherman's Association, Correspondence, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Antigua, Historical and Archaeological Society, Correspondence, 1986-1988, 1991-1996, 1999-2000, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - Antigua, Historical and Archaeological Society, Newsletters, Reports, and Information, 1985-1994, 2004-2012, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 139-140)
  - Antigua, Organization for Agricultural Development, Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - Antigua, Racer Conservation Project (Offshore Islands Conservation Programme), 1996, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Antigua, Racer Conservation Project (Offshore Islands Conservation Programme), 2000-2010, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 143-146)
  - Antigua and Barbuda, Small Farmers Association, Questionnaire, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - Aves Island, 1968, 1970, 1973-1974, 1976, 1978, 1991, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Bahamas, General Information, 1971, 1976, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 150)
  - Bahamas, General Information, 1973, 1981, 1985, 1987, 1989, 1994, 1998, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 151-152)
  - Bahamas, Clippings, 1997-2000, 2002, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - Bahamas, Agriculture, Disaster Planning, Electrification Project, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 154-155)
  - Bahamas, Bahamas National Trust, Information on Trust's Land Management, 1976, 1983, 1988, 1991, 1998-1999, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Barbados, General Information, Physical Development Planning, 1959, 1969, 1973, 1977, 1980, 1988, 2000, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 157)
  - Barbados, General Information, Physical Development Planning, 1970, 1974-1975, 1983, 1988, 1991, 1998, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 158-159)
  - Barbados, Clippings, 1996-1999, 2002, 2007-2010 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Barbados, History, Barbados Museum, Historical Society, and The Barbados National Trust, 1964, 1970, 1973-1974, 1976, 1978, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 161-163)
  - Barbados, History, Barbados Museum, Historical Society, and The Barbados National Trust, 1997, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Barbados, Barbados: A Coral Paradise, Angelique Brathwaite, Hazel Oxenford, and Ramon Roach, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Barbados, Environmental Legislation, Environmental Institutions, Marine Environment, and Fisheries, 1967, 1978-1980, 1982-1989, 1998-2001, 2010, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 166-168)
  - Barbados, Barbados Environmental Association, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Barbados, Barbados Museum and Historical Society, Correspondence, 1987, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Barbados, Barbados Museum and Historical Society, Mini-Grant, 1987, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Barbados, Barbados National Trust, 1976, 1983, 1988-1989, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Barbados, East Caribbean Institute of Development, 1986, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Belize, General Information, 1973, 1979, 1982-1984, 1986-1988, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 174-175)
  - Belize, Coastal and Marine Resources, 1966, 1969-1971, 1974, 1977, 1979, 1985, 1987, 1989, 1992-1993, 1995-1996, 1998, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 176-179)
  - Bermuda, General Information, 1976, 1993-1994, 1997-1999, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 180-183, Folder 1)
    Oversized materials have been removed. Please contact a RAC archivist to view material. FA1200:001
  - Bermuda, Clippings, 1995, 1997, 1999-2005 (Box 15, Folder 184)
  - Bermuda, Environment, Biodiversity, 1990-1991, 1993, 1996-1999, 2003, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 185-186)
  - Bermuda, Environment, Biodiversity-A Land Management Plan for Smith's Island, Bermuda, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Bermuda, Environment, Biodiversity, 1994, 1996-1999 (Box 16, Folder 187)
  - Bermuda, Bermuda National Trust, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 188)
  - Bermuda, Workshop on Renewable & Alternative Energy Technologies for Bermuda and Other Small Islands, 2000 June 5-6 (Box 16, Folder 189)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), General Information, 1974, 1976-1977, 1980, 1983, 1985, 1987-1988, 2001, 2003-2004, 2009, 2012, 2014 (Box 16, Folder 190-193)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), General Information, 1972-1973, 1975, 1996, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 194-197)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Clippings, 1981-1982, 1987, 1989-2004 (Box 17, Folder 198-199)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Clippings, 2005-2014, 2016 (Box 18, Folder 200-204)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Biodiversity, Parks and Protected Areas, 1976, 1999-2000, 2002, 2010, 2012, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Biodiversity, Parks and Protected Areas, 1954, 1971, 1973, 1976, 1978, 1980, 1982, 1986-1987, 1989, 1992, 1996, 1998, 2001-2011, 2013-2015 (Box 19, Folder 206-211)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Biodiversity, Parks and Protected Areas, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Environment Policy, Development Planning, 1976, 1978, 1993, 1995, 1997-1998, 2001-2007, 2009-2013 (Box 20, Folder 213-218)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Environment Policy, Development Planning-EIA Training Course in the British Virgin Islands, 2009 February 18-20 (Box 20, Folder 216)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Environment Policy, Development Planning, 2010, 2013 (Box 21, Folder 219-220)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Environment Policy, Development Planning, Reports, 1994, 2002, 2004, 2006, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 221-224)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Environment Policy, Development Planning, Reports, 2006, 2013 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Legislation, 1973, 1986-1987, 2000, 2003-2004, 2006, 2008-2010, 2012 (Box 22, Folder 226-228)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Marine Archaeology, 1968, 1971, 1973, 1976, 1983-1987,1999, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 229-230)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Marine Archaeology, British Virgin Islands (BVI) Marine Awareness, Vol. 2 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Marine Resources, Coastal Zone Management, 1971, 1973, 1979, 1981, 1984-1985, 1990-1992, 1999-2000, 2002-2014 (Box 23, Folder 232-237)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Marine Resources, Coastal Zone Management-BVI Oil Spill Risk, 2003 November (Box 23, Folder 233)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Marine Resources, Coastal Zone Management-Persevering Nature's Secrets, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 233)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Tourism Marine Industry, 1978, 1980, 1987, 1995-1996, 2001, 2004, 2006-2008, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 238-243)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Tourism Marine Industry (Box 25, Folder 244)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Tourism Marine Industry-Sustainable Tourism Thesis, Angela Burnett Penn (Box 25, Folder 244)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Articles on Richard Branson, 2007-2010, 2012-2014 (Box 25, Folder 245)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, 1968, 1971, 1973-1976, 1980, 1985, 1987-1988, 1991, 1993, 1997, 2001, 2003-2007, 2009-2013 (Box 25, Folder 246-250)
    Oversized materials have been removed. Please contact a RAC archivist to view material.
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, Photographs, 1968, 1971, 1973-1976, 1980, 1985, 1987-1988, 1991, 1993, 1997, 2001, 2003-2007, 2009-2013 (Box 187, Folder 2169-2170)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, 1970, 1972, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 251-252)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, Development Proposal, 1973-1974, 2014 (Box 26, Folder 253-254)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, Development Proposal, Photographs, 1973 (Box 187, Folder 2171)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Anegada, Anegada Sea Turtle Recovery, A Community Assessment, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 255)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Atoll, Atoll Research Bulletin, 1971 February 16, 1975 August 6 (Box 26, Folder 256-257)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Atoll, Atoll Research Bulletin, 1979 November (Box 27, Folder 258)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Beef Island, Development Project, Reports and Information, 1974, 1996, 1998, 2000, 2005-2013 (Box 27, Folder 259-263)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Beef Island, Development Project, Reports and Information, 2004-2006, 2012 (Box 28, Folder 264)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Beef island, Beef Island Airport Construction, Island Erosion, 2000-2003 (Box 28, Folder 265)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Jost Van Dyke, 1969, 1978, 1991, 1998, 2000, 2002, 2004-2006, 2008-2011, 2013 (Box 28, Folder 266-267)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Little Jost Van Dyke, John Lettsom Birthplace, Correspondence and Research, 1969-1970, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 268)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Mosquito Island, Environmental Impact Assessment, 2008, 2010-2011 (Box 28, Folder 269-270)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Mosquito Island, Environmental Impact Assessment-Mosquito Island Full EIA (Box 28, Folder 269)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Mosquito Island, Construction Environmental Management Plan, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 271)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Necker Island (Box 29, Folder 272)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, 1977-1978, 1983, 1993, 1997, 1999,2001, 2003-2004, 2007, 2014 (Box 29, Folder 273-274, Folder 1)
    Oversized materials have been removed. Please contact a RAC archivist to view material. FA1200:004
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, General Correspondence, 1968-2000 (Box 29, Folder 276-277)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Junior Coakley, 1996-1998 (Box 29, Folder 278)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Jonathan Hendricks, 1973, 1978-1980, 1984-1987, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 279)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Nehmiah (Nipps) Hendricks, 1989-1996 (Box 30, Folder 280)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, Resortscapes, Inc., 1997 (Box 30, Folder 281)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, Photographs and Slides, 1976-1977, 1979-1982, 1985-1987, 1994, 1997, 2000-2002 (Box 30, Folder 282)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, Photographs and Slides, 2000 June 5 (Box 30, Folder 282)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, Photographs and Slides, 2000 June 5 (Box 30, Folder 282)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Sandy Cay, Photographs and Slides, 1976-1977, 1979-1982, 1985-1987, 1994-1997, 2000-2002, 2007 April (Box 188, Folder 2172-2180)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Gorda, North Sound, 1970, 1972, 1974, 1980, 1982, 1986, 1995, 1999, 2001-2004, 2007-2016 (Box 30, Folder 283-285)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Gorda, North Sound-Nail Bay, "Private Jetty" and Artificial Barrier Reef, 2009 November (Box 30, Folder 285)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Gorda, Articles, 2012 (Box 30, Folder 286)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Gorda, Reports, 1972, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 287)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Gorda, Oil Nut Peninsula, Environmental Impact Assessment, 2000-2003, 2008, 2010 (Box 30, Folder 288)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Norman Island, 1999-2001, 2014 (Box 31, Folder 289)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Site Specific, Paraquita Bay and Trellis Bay, 1990, 1996-1997, 2001, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 290)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Site Specific, Tortola and Sea Cows Bay, 1995, 2001-2002, 2010-2011, 2014-2015 (Box 31, Folder 291-293)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Cam Bay, Cane Garden Bay, Scrub Island, and Peter Island, 1996-1997, 2005-2011, 2014-2015 (Box 31, Folder 294)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Site Specific, Guana Science, 1986, 1996, 2007-2008, 2010, 2012, 2014-2016 (Box 31, Folder 295)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Association of Reef Keepers, 1997, 1999-2008, 2010, 2014 (Box 31, Folder 296)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Correspondence, 1991-1995, 1999, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 297)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Information, Publications, and Reports, 1991-1994, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 298)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Grant Fund by Members' Donations, 1992-1994 (Box 32, Folder 299)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Grant for Computerization, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 300)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Grant for Horticultural Course, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 301)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Botanic Society, Grant for Upgrading the Library, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 302)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Hotel and Commerce Association, Questionnaire, 1986, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 303)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Hotel and Commerce Association, Newsletters, Reports, and Information, 1986, 1988-1990 (Box 32, Folder 304)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Hotel and Commerce Association, Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 32, Folder 305)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Hotel and Commerce Association, Mini-Grant, 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 306)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Correspondence, 1986-1989, 1991-1995, 1998-2002, 2004, 2007-2008, 2010-2012, 2014 (Box 32, Folder 307)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Newsletters, Reports, and Information, 1984-1986-1987, 1991, 1993-1994, 1996, 1998-2005, 2008-2012 (Box 32, Folder 308)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) Falconwood/Jarecki Funded Grants, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 309)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Historical Stone Masonry Workshop Grant, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 310)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Financial Statements, 1994, 1998-2005, 2007 (Box 33, Folder 311)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Annual Reports, 2002-2004, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 312)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks Trust, Mandate and Programme, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 313)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks, USA, Correspondence, 1999, 2002-2003 (Box 33, Folder 214)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), British Virgin Islands (BVI) National Parks, USA, Information, Documentation, etc., 2002 (Box 33, Folder 315)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), East Caribbean Institute of Development, 1986, 1991-1992, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Green Virgin Islands, 2009-2011, 2016 (Box 33, Folder 317)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Historical Society, Questionnaire, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 318)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Historical Society, Correspondence, 1987-1988, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 319)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Island Erosion, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 320)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Jost Van Dyke Preservation Society, Correspondence, 1991-1993, 2003-2005, 2007, 2010-2014 (Box 33, Folder 321)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Jost Van Dyke Preservation Society, Information, 1978, 2003-2005, 2007-2009, 2012, 2015-2016 (Box 33, Folder 322)
  - British Virgin Islands (BVI), Virgin Islands Environmental Council, 2007-2010 (Box 33, Folder 323)
  - Cayman Islands, 1955, 1963-1965, 1967, 1970-1971, 1975, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 324)
  - Cayman Islands, 1971, 1973-1974, 1985-1986, 1992, 1995-1997, 1999-2002, 2008 (Box 34, Folder 325-326)
  - Cayman Islands, Cayman Islands National Trust, 1990, 1992, 1994-1999 (Box 34, Folder 327)